fredyherman12@gmail.com

FREDERICK HERMAN

Henderson, NV 89074

702-815-4860

SUMMARY

I am an individual who has 9 years of hospitality experience. I am a quick learner who has always been able to adapt to changing environments and trends. I understand that hard work is necessary, but will only take you so far. I have leadership qualities that change the culture and a attitude of the employees under me. I have solved many issues at many stores and believe that proactive management is better than reactive management.

SKILLS

Management
Labor and food cost control
Administrative support
MS Office

Restaurant operations management Hiring and training Communications

EXPERIENCE

RESTAURANT GENERAL MANAGER | 12/2019 to 08/2020 **Loves Travel Stops - Ely, NV**

- Upheld restaurant standards for food and beverage quality, team member engagement, financial goals, standard operating procedures and guest experiences.
- Monitored and trained service team members on suggestive selling practices and continuous sales growth of beverage, appetizer, add-on and desserts.
- Scheduled and directed staff in daily work assignments to maximize productivity.
- Performed accurate monthly inventories of supplies and equipment, including food, beverage, paper items.

RESTAURANT MANAGER | 12/2016 to 11/2019 Amirian Management Company - Las Vegas, NV

- General Manager in charge of restaurant daily results.
 - Created a work environment based on the companies four pillars to success, Employees, Operations, Guest Experience & Cash Flow.
 - Trained and maintained a roster of 40 employees, scheduled to provide smooth operations and creating unique guest experiences, to achieve a higher cash flow.
 - Strengthened low performing store bringing it to a consistent top 5 results driven store (franchise's formula)
 - Built a loyal team bringing in the lowest turn overrate in company, held for 2 consecutive years
 - Increased net sales by 3.23% (1.007m vs 1.039m) and transaction count by 4.63% (87063 vs 91097) fiscal year 2017
 - Decreased labor by 0.82% (21.04% vs 20.22%) and reduced food cost by 1.21% (34.16% vs 32.95%)

IT SUPPORT | 04/2019 to 10/2019

Amirian Management Company - Las Vegas, NV

- Supported 18 restaurants with hardware and software related IT issues
- · Maintain a healthy relationship between all vendors required for company to operate
- Installed and troubleshooted emerging technologies to make for more efficient operations
- Manage work and device policies for management team

ASSISTANT MANAGER | 03/2016 to 12/2016 Frsco Corp - Las Vegas, NV

- In charge of scheduling and inventory.
- I assisted General Manager in daily operations providing the necessary training for all employees and assisting where needed.
- In charge of updating all Product on Promotion postings, price updates, and communicating these changes to all employees.
- Increased Full Operations Review score by 12%
- Trained new staff and retrained previous staff on brand standards.

COMPUTER SALES ASSOCIATE | 09/2015 to 03/2016 Fry's Electronics Inc. - Las Vegas, NV

- Provide the best possible sales experience, from the moment they walk in, to the moment they leave.
- Provide the client with options, and teach them about the products that they may be considering.
- Create a transparent environment, an environment where the client knows the benefits and drawbacks of each product.
- Top 5 salesman for department Q4 2015
- Highest GP (Gross Pro t) Q4 2015.

ASSISTANT MANAGER | 08/2010 to 09/2015 Snowed Inn LLC - Las Vegas, NV

- In charge of scheduling and inventory.
- I assisted General Manager in daily operations providing the necessary training for all employees and assisting where needed.
- In charge of updating all Product on Promotion postings, price updates, and communicating these changes to all employees.
- Crew member of the year for my location 2011
- Swing manager of the year for my location 2012

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

College Of Southern Nevada - Las Vegas, NV Some College (No Degree)

Business Management, IT

Sierra Vista High School - Las Vegas, NV High School Diploma 06/2009

CERTIFICATIONS

ServSafe